Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office. George Black Papers, 1968-1989.
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- JWT-Allgemein Series, Restricted, 1978-1986
  Contains typed and handwritten letters, telexes, telegrams and faxes, memoranda, manuscripts, clippings, articles, notes, copy, client lists, advertisements, printed material, receipts and invoices, programs, invitations, agendas, and other documents relating to policies and daily operations of the Frankfurt Office. Arranged alphabetically by subdivision, then chronologically.
  - Art Director's Club (ADC): (Box 22)
    - 1981-1986, (3 folders) (Box 22)
    - Correspondence, 1981-1986, (5 folders) (Box 22)
  - Director's Meeting, 1979-1986, (2 folders) (Box 23)
  - Diverse, 1978-1985, (4 folders) (Box 23)
  - Ernennungen, Umorganisation, 1980-1983 (Box 23)
  - Ernennungen, Organisation, 1985 (Box 23)
  - Events, 1979-1985, (3 folders) (Box 23)
  - Initiative, 1982 (Box 23)
  - Memoranda, 1980-1986, (4 folders) (Box 23)
  - Presse, 1985-1986 (Box 23)
  - Visitors, 1978-1986, (2 folders) (Box 23)
  - Vorträge, Tagungen, 1986 (Box 23)
- Memoranda/Haus-Mitteilungen Series, Restricted, 1984-1988
  Consists of typed and handwritten letters, memoranda, telexes, telegrams and faxes, photographs, programs, speeches, invitations, printed material, advertisements, collateral, client lists, invitations, video and tape scripts, broadside newsletters, clippings, travel documents, and other materials relating to policies and daily operations of the Frankfurt Office. Arranged alphabetically by subdivision, then chronologically.
  - 1984, (4 folders) (Box 23)
  - Portrait, 1984, (3 folders) (Box 23)
  - 1987, (4 folders) (Box 23)
  - WPP Takeover, (2 folders) (Box 23)
  - 1988 (Box 23)
  - 1988, (3 folders) (Box 24)
- Personnel Series, Restricted, 1976-1988
  Holds typed and handwritten correspondence, interview minutes, job descriptions, resumes, evaluations, consultant billings, policy information regarding international transfers, raises, loans, vacation time, JWT's staffing system, and other related issues. The series contains typed and handwritten letters, memoranda, job descriptions, resumes, telexes and telegrams, transfer agreements, and other documents relating to JWT hiring and employment policies. Arranged chronologically, then alphabetically.
  - 1976-1982 (Box 24)
  - 1976-1982, Current, A-Z, (4 folders) (Box 24)
  - 1977-1981, Bewerbungen:
    - Consultants (Box 24)
    - A-Z, (4 folders) (Box 24)
  - 1979-1982, Unit Staff (Box 24)
  - 1982-1988, Bewerbungen, A-Z, (5 folders) (Box 24)
  - 1983-1988, Correspondence (Box 24)
  - 1983-1988, (2 folders) (Box 24)
  - 1983-1988, A-Z, (3 folders) (Box 24)
- Farewell Series, Restricted, 1981-1988; bulk 1981, 1986, and 1988
  Contains letters, telexes and telegrams, memoranda, notes, guest lists, invitations, programs, speeches, printed material, menus, photographs, and receipts relating to all aspects of retirement parties and other official commemorations for senior executives. Arranged alphabetically by executive, then chronologically.
  - George Black: (Box 24)
    - 1981, Member of the Board (Box 24)
    - 1984, 30th Anniversary (Box 24)
  - George Black, 1988, (2 folders) (Box 25)
  - Peter Gilow, 1988 (Box 25)
  - Denis Lanigan, 1986 (Box 25)
- Presse/Articles Series, Restricted, 1980-1988, bulk 1982-1988
  Contains typed and handwritten letters, manuscripts, clippings, articles, press releases, notes, and interviews with, by or about George Black. Arranged chronologically.
  - 1980-1988, (3 folders) (Box 25)
- Organizations Series, Restricted, 1980-1982, bulk 1981
  Contains typed letters, articles, minutes, reports, invoices and receipts, agendas, and other documents relating to professional and other organizations of which Black was a member. Arranged alphabetically by organization, then chronologically.
  - EAAA: (Box 25)
    - 1980-1982 (Box 25)
    - 1980-1981, Correspondence (Box 25)
- Seminars Series, Restricted, 1976-1981
  Comprised of typed and handwritten letters, memoranda, telexes and telegrams, programs, agendas, attendee lists, speeches, presentation scripts, invoice receipts, photographs, printed material, and other documentation relating to seminars attended by JWT employees. Arranged chronologically, then alphabetically by seminar.
  - 1979-1981, Creative orientation (Box 25)
  - 1976-1981, Noordwijk-James W. Young (Box 25)
- Writings and Speeches Series, Restricted, 1968-1987
  Contains index lists. Arranged chronologically.
  - 1968-1987, Indices (Box 25)
  - 1982-1983, MRC List (Box 25)
- Acquisitions Series, Restricted, 1977-1982
  Contains letters, memoranda, notes, telexes and telegrams, advertisements, reports, and other documents relating to the acquisition by JWT of subsidiary agencies. Arranged alphabetically.
  - 1977-1981 (Box 25)
  - 1980-1981, Austria (Box 25)
  - 1981-1982, Getas (Box 25)
- Subsidiaries & Divisions Series, Restricted, 1978-1988, bulk 1982-1988
  Contains letters, memoranda, telexes and telegrams, notes, press releases, newsletters, sales agreements, guestlist, flyers, and other documents relating to JWT subsidiaries and divisions. Arranged alphabetically by company.
  - 1982-1985 (Box 25)
  - Basis research, 1982-1987 (Box 25)
  - JWT Corporate Communications, 1982-1985 (Box 25)
  - Deltakos, 1979-1987 (Box 25)
  - JWT Direct, 1985-1988 (Box 25)
  - JWT Düsseldorf, 1982-1987 (Box 25)
  - JWT Hamburg, 1982-1988 (Box 25)
  - Hill & Knowlton, 1982-1988, (2 folders) (Box 25)
  - Proservice, 1988 (Box 25)
  - T&A, 1978-1984 (Box 25)
- Finance Series, Restricted, 1977-1988
  Holds financial data, targets and planning estimates, billing and cost summaries, audit reports, operating results, executive personal expenses, executive report summaries with recommendations, and JWT stock. Contains typed and handwritten letters, memoranda, news releases, telexes and telegrams, audit reports, Profit Plans, Three-Year Plans, Operating Results, and other documents relating to JWT-Frankfurt's Finance Department. Arranged alphabetically by subdivision, then chronologically.
  - 1983-1984, (5 folders) (Box 25)
  - Audit report, 1986 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1982, Mar., (6 folders) (Box 25)
  - Correspondence, 1982, Apr.-1988, (7 folders) (Box 26)
  - GWA-prognose, 1981 (Box 26)
  - Kostenrechnung, 1985-1988, (4 folders) (Box 26)
  - Operating results, 1977-1983, (3 folders) (Box 26)
  - Personal expenses, 1979-1988, (2 folders) (Box 26)
  - Plandaten, 1980-1982 (Box 26)
  - Prof. Incentive plan, 1986 (Box 26)
  - Profit plan, 1980-1988, (6 folders) (Box 26)
  - Targets, 1985-1988, (2 folders) (Box 26)
  - Three-Year plan, 1977-1979 (Box 26)